Guide to the Robert J. Havighurst Papers 1921-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series I: Biographical Materials
  - Greek Civilization Notebook-Experimental College (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Greek Civilization-Experimental College (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Meiklejohn Education Foundation (1 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Meiklejohn Education Foundation (2 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Meiklejohn Education Foundation (3 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Meiklejohn Experimental College (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Meiklejohn Experimental College (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Meiklejohn (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Meiklejohn Institutes and Foundations (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Meiklejohn Foundation, Experimental College (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Experimental College (1 of 2) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Experimental College (2 of 2) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Teaching of Freedom: Alexander Meiklejohn in his own Words (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Manuscripts (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Meetings (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Papers on Educational Reform, 1930-32 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 1928-1932, Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - 1928-1932, Class Reunions, Meiklejohn (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Advisers of the Experimental College, Feb 1932 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Hill, Learning and Living (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Meiklejohn, The Experimental College (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Beecher, ‘And I Will Be Heard’ (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Subseries 1: General by Date
    - Job stuff (1 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Job stuff (2 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous to 1960 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous after 1900 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Letters 1986-1991 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2: General by Name
    - A-Z, Miscellaneous, 1960-1984 (1 of 3) (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - A-Z, Miscellaneous, 1960-1984 (2 of 3) (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - A-Z, Miscellaneous, 1960-1984 (3 of 3) (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - A, Miscellaneous, 1964-1985 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Academic Freedom, 1960-1961, 1983 (1 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Academic Freedom, 1960-1961, 1983 (2 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Action for Independent Maturity, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Action-Learning Programs, 1972-1974 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Action-Learning Projects, 1966-1970 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Adams, A. E. [Betty], 1954-1985 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Addison-Wesley Publishing Company, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - ADA Advisory Committee (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Advocates for Indian Education, 1973-1975 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Aerospace Research, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Aerospace Research, Office of Aerospace Research, Scientific Advisory Group Meeting, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Aging: An International Annual, International Journal of Aging and Human Development, 1972-1982 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Alaska Methodist University, 1962-1968 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Albert Schweitzer College, 1952-1972 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Alfred Jaeger, Inc., 1985 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Alice Lloyd College, 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - American Association of Retired Persons, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1947-1953, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - American Educational Research Association, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - American Medical Association, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - American Psychological Association, 1957-1963, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - American Sociological Association, certificate, 1959, 1967, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Arlington Public Schools, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development, 1955-1980 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Australia, 1963-1974 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Boy Scouts of America, 1968-1975 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Boy Scouts Committee (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous C (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Callihan, James, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Carnegie Corporation, 1952-1977 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Carp, Frances M., 1979 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Center for Applied Research in Education, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Cesa-Bianchi, Marcello, 1970-1975 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Chala, Siegfried S., 1967-1974 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Chicago Association for Retarded Children, 1971-1983 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Chicago Urban League, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Christian Action Ministry, 1975-1979 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Church Federation of Greater Chicago, 1950-1956 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Coleman, James S., 1972 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Corsini, Raymond J., 1977 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Cronbach, Lee J., 1972 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Dieckmann, Erwin, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Earl and Esther Johnson Fund, 1981-1985 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Education, 1951-1967 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - F, Miscellaneous, 1961-1983 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Field, Henry, 1962-1979 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Fielding Institute, 1979-1983 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Fister, Jack L. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Focus on aging, 1976-1979 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Food, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Ford Foundation, 1959-1974 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Fordham University, 1967-1979 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Fordham University, "Time for a Moratorium on Negative Criticisms of the Schools," by RJH, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Free Street Theater, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Freedom, 1952, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Fuchs, Estelle, 1968-1982 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - G, Miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Gateway Vistas, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Glass, Thomas, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Glick, Ruth and Thomas F., 1974-1977 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Gun Control, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - H, Miscellaneous, 1960-1985 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Haley, Frederick T., 1970-1975 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Henry, William E., 1955-1969 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Hepner, Ethel M., 1962-1977 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Herrick, Mary, 1967-1977 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Hispanic American Historical Review, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Holsinger, Donald B., 1973-1976 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Hyde Park Neighborhood Club, 1959-1984 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - I, Miscellaneous, 1975-1982 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Illinois Department on Aging, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Illinois Gerontology Consortium, 1980-1981 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Illinois Psychological Association, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Illinois State Psychiatric Institute, 1982-1984 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - India Ph.D.s, 1976-1985 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Institute for Social and Psychological Studies, 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - International Association of Applied Psychology, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - International Center for Integrative Studies, 1973-1979 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - International Organization for the Study of Human Development, 1967-1980 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - International Review of Education, 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - J, Miscellaneous, 1975-1979 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Japan, 1971-1983 (3) (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Japan, business trips, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Japan, thank you notes, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Community Centers, 1977-1980 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Journal of Applied Developmental Psychology, 1978-1981 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Journal of Genetic Psychology, 1959-1967 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Journal of Gerontology, 1969-1981 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - JWK International Corporation, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - K, Miscellaneous, 1952-1982 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Kansas City Business, Evy and Paul Bowman, 1962-1982 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Kansas City List of Publications, 1961-1974 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Kappa Delta Pi, 1979-1982 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Kappa Phi Kappa, certificate, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Kleinfeld, Judith, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - L, Miscellaneous, 1964-1982 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Latin American Studies Association, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Lauwerys, Joseph A., 1953-1976 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Lehr, Ursula, 1970-1983 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Levine, Arthur, book review by Havighurst, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Levinson, Daniel J., 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Liddle, Ginny and Gordon, 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Life style transitions related to personality type after age fifty, 1960-1975 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Lingle, Kendall I., 1978-1983 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Little League Baseball, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Loeb, Martin B., 1980-1984 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Longitudinal research, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - M, Miscellaneous, 1969-1985 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Maesen, William A., 1976 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Mayor's Office for Senior Citizens, Chicago Multidisciplinary Center of Gerontology, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - McDonald, William J., 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Buyer Behavior and Use of Time in Later Life (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Meiklejohn, Donald, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Mentally ill, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Metropolitan Chicago Coalition on Aging, 1980-1983 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Meyers, Dorothy, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Miller, Kenneth M., 1967-1981 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Miller, Marian H., 1982 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Milwaukee Public Schools, Steven Baruch, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Ministries in Public Education, 1979-1983 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Minnesota Systems Research, 1973-1975 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Monsen, Dale, 1972, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Montessori School Centennial, 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Moral Development, 1966-1977 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - N, Miscellaneous, 1965-1983 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - National Academy of Education, 1974-1985 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - National Directory of Sociology of Education and Educational Folder 15: Sociology, 1970- 1976 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - National Research Council, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - National Association of Human Development-Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - National Association of Human Development-Other (1 of 3) (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - National Association of Human Development-Other (2 of 3) (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - National Association of Human Development-Other (3 of 3) (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - National Urban Coalition, 1970-1978 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - O, Miscellaneous, 1973-1980 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Ohio State University, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Oliver, Andree, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Operation Able, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Operations Research, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - P, Miscellaneous, 1968-1982 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Paraguides, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Park Forest College, 1964-1965 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Parkyn, George W., 1973-1977 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Pearse, Andrew, 1965-1966 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - People of interest, c.v.s, 1979-1980 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Percy, Charles H., 1972-1983 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Permissions to reprint, 1959-1984 (1 of 3) (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Permissions to reprint, 1959-1984 (2 of 3) (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Permissions to reprint, 1959-1984 (3 of 3) (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Phi Delta Kappa, 1968, 1979-1980 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Phi Delta Kappa, Derek L. Burleson, 1982-1984 (2) (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Phi Delta Kappa, Committee on the Mission of Special Phi Delta Kappa Publications, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Phi Delta Kappa, lecture series, 1976-1985 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Phi Delta Kappa, local chapter, 1975-1980 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Pilley, John, 1953-1965 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Pomfret School, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Powell, John W., 1956-1958, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Powers, Sally, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Productivity After Age 70, research assistants, 1974-1977 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - R, Miscellaneous, 1962-1981 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Rabinical and Talmudic Schools, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Redmond, James, 1966-1975 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Developing Conscience and a Scale of Values (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Readings in Social Foundations of Education, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Readings in Society and Education, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Records Office, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - "Report on a Conference in Washington Concerning Our Proposal for a Training Program in Adult Life and Aging," 1964 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Requests for reprints, 1972-1979 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Research Forecasts, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Research Commission on Pupil Personnel Services, 1962-1967 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Richmond schools, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Riner, Reed, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Q (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Rivlin, Harry N., 1980 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1953-1982 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Rodgers, Carl R. and Helen, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Roosevelt University, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - S, Miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Sage Publications, 1969-1981 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Saxe, Richard W., 1974-1975 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Schiff, Michel, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Senior volunteers in the public schools, 1975-1977 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Shanas, Ethel, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Shimbori, Michiya, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Siegler, Mark, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Silberman, Samuel J., 1979-1981 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Smithsonian Institution Archives, 1970-1973 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Smolic-Krkovic, Nada, 1972-1977 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - "Social Competence and Middle-Aged People," 1957-1960 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Social Research, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Social Security Administration, 1961-1963 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Society and Education, 1974-1977 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - "Society and Education in Chicago," 1964-1972 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Society for Psychological Study of Social Issues, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Society for Research in Child Development, 1973-1982 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Society for the Scientific Study of Religion, 1965-1977 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Sociological Abstracts, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Sociology of Education, 1976-1979 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Sound Seminars, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Spencer Foundation, 1972-1978 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Shoshana, Stiftel (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Speeches in Spanish (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Spencer Foundation (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Sperb, Dalilla C., 1966-1980 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Stone Lectures (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Stone Lectures, Princeton Theological Seminary, 1962-1964 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Student Research Project, 1948-1949 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Student Research Project, Personnel, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Student Values Project, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Study of the professions, 1961-1962 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Survey of Gifted Children, 1953-1956 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - T, Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Thomae and Lehr (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Taba, Hilda, 1942-1978 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Thomae, festschrift, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Twentieth Century Fund, 1973-1975 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Turnbach, Sister Marie, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - U, Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - United Christian Community Services, 1974-1977 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, Southwest India Report, 1974-1976 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service, 1973-1977 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - U.S. Office of Education, 1960-1979 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - U.S. Government Consultant (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - University Microfilms, 1969-1975 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - University of Alaska, 1974-1983 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - University of Chicago, Alumni College, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - University of Chicago, Office of Special Programs, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - University of Chicago Library, gifts, 1967-1989 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - University of Florida, 1959-1961 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - University of Maryland, 1974-1980 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - University of Melbourne, 1954-1963 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - University of Michigan, 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - University of Southern California, 1954-1964 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Urban Training Center for Christian Mission, 1966-1968 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Voice of America, 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - W, Miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - W. Clement Jessie V. Stone Foundation, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Walberg, Herbert J., 1978 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Wadsworth, Homer C., 1971-1984 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Ward, Virgil, 1973-1974 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Washington University, 1966-1971 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Watts, Betty, 1973-1985 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Welford, A. T., 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - West Virginia, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Western Illinois University, 1978-1979 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Wheeler, D. K., 1955-1961 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - White, John K., 1974 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Who Shall Be Educated? 1941-1972 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Woodlawn, 1963-1964, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Work Study Students, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - World Bank, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - World Publishing Company, Jefferson Encyclopedia, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Wright Institute, 1976-1979 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Wynne, Edward A., 1974-1980 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - X, Y, Z, Miscellaneous, 1967-1983 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Yarling, Roland R., 1975, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - YMCA, Adult Committee, 1966-1969 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - YMCA, Family Project, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3: Former Students
    - Arasteh, Josephine D., 1960-1965 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Bigart, Robert J., 1971-1975 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Chay, Josephine S., 1965-1966 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Kim, Sun Ho, 1960-1967 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Kornacker, Mildred, 1964-1971 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Orr, Betty, 1963 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Pasca, Richard E., 1971-1976 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Rich, Robert M., 1965-1970 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Rosner, Tena T., 1974 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Sterns, Maurice A., 1969-1974 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Relationships of Attitudes to Outcomes (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 4: Presses and Publishers
    - Academic Press, 1976-1982 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Allyn Bacon, 1957-1980 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Allyn Bacon, Business Matters, 1955-1980 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Allyn Bacon, Metropolitan Development and Education, 1968-1974 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Allyn Bacon, Readings in Society and Education, 1964-1975 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Junior College (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Society and Education (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Brazil Archives, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - David McKay Company, 1953-1978 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Doubleday Company, 1970-1982 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Faculty News Bulletin, 1960-1979 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Goodyear Publishing Company, 1974-1980 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Grolier, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Houghton-Mifflin Company, Cross-National Studies With Psychological Instruments, 1963-1978 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Houghton-Mifflin Company, Becoming and Educator Father of the Man, 1947-1977 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Human Development Committee (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - John Wiley Sons, 1958-1978 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Jossey-Bass Publishers, 400 Losers: Delinquent Boys in High School, 1966-1980 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Journals sold, 1958-1977 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Little, Brown and Company, 1966-1977 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Longman, 1977-1983 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Longmans, Green Company, Midwest Veteran Back Home, 1951-1955 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Meaning of Work, publications, 1952-1963 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Oxford University Press, 1964-1972 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Plenum Publishing Corporation, 1979-1985 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Praeger Publishers, 1969-1973 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - S. Karger AG, 1963-1980 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - SAGE Publications, 1969-1984 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Science Research Associates, 1960-1982 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Science Research Associates, Your Activities and Attitudes, 1949-1955 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - University Microfilms International, 1976-1982 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1955-1984 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - University of Pittsburgh Press, 1962-1982 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 5: University of Chicago
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Westminster Press, 1964-1970 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Wilcox Follett Company, Effective Use of Older Workers, 1951-1961 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Dean's report, 1956-1976 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Faculty report of outside earnings, 1945-1953 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Salary arrangements, 1965-1969 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Teaching plans, 1962-1974 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Committee on Human Development
      - Abstracts, MAs, PhDs, 1955-1962 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Administration, 1956-1958 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Bradburn Committee, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - News of alumni, 1975, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Department of Behavioral Sciences, 1974-1985 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Departmental histories, mission, 1944-1986 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Faculty meetings, 1976-1986 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Human Development 412, student papers, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Human Development Bulletin, 1954-1965 (Box 37, Folder 13)
      - Human Development Publication Fund, 1977-1985 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Research, manuscripts, 1944-1988, Sub-subseries 3: Department of Education (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 1958-1979 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - RJH, a Pioneer in Social Gerontology (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - HD Research in Progress (Box 38, Folder 5)
- Series III: General Education
  - Student Journal of HD, Spring 1960 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Warner, Mildred-Warner Fund (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Warner, Mildred-Book (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Warner, Mildred (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Education-Miscellaneous (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - General Education (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - NSSE Expenses (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Adult Education Appointments (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report (ed) (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Application for Admission to Candidacy-Advisor’s Notice, Manual of Directions (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Business-Department of Education (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Educational Psych (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Textbook ED 312: The Growth and Development of School Children (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Faculty-Education (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Horton, Aimee Isgrig (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Matenza, Janice Grow (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Matthews, Charles V. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Olson, George E. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Publication Committee-Education (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Should You Go To College? Mss, Drafts, Notes (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Counselor as Behavioral Scientist, MS, April 15, 1965 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Schools for the 60s-The Profession Speaks on Crucial Curriculum Decisions, Sept 1962 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Science Education-Miscellaneous Mss, notes, correspondence (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Scientific Talent-Miscellaneous Mss (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - What is Life Adjustment Education? Sept 1949 (Box 40, Folder 4)